Evangelia Tremou, Ph.D.



evangelia.tremou@obspm.fr



Website



in Linkedin



Scientific Interests

 My research focuses on the physics of compact objects and radio transients with radio observations from large radio interferometers. I am interested in deep radio surveys that allow us to explore the time-variable radio sky (explosions, collisions, disruption events) and constrain the rates and the physical mechanisms that drive these events. I am also involved in execution of surveys with next generation telescopes (SKA precursors) such as MeerKAT and NenuFAR and I am particularly interested in advanced radio calibration and imaging techniques.

Employment History

2020 - today 2017 - 2019 Research Associate/PSL fellow. Paris Observatory, Meudon, France

Research Associate. CEA-Saclay and Université Paris VII (Labex UnivEarthS), Gif-Sur-Yvette, France

2015 - 2017

Research Associate. Michigan State University MI, USA

• Research Associate. Yonsei University Observatory, Seoul, S.Korea 2012 - 2014



Education

2008 - 2011

Ph.D Physics, University of Cologne, Germany



Thesis title: Spectroscopic studies on AGNs and High angular resolution in the NIR: The construction of an imaging beam combiner for the LBT

2002 - 2007

B.Sc. Physics, Aristotle University Thessaloniki Thesis title: HII regions detection in Local Group Census



Skills

Languages

Greek (native), English (professional working proficiency), German (elementary proficiency), French (beginner).

Astronomical Tools

Virtual Observatory (VO) tools, AIPS, Difmap, CASA, DDFacet, WSClean, AOFlagger, GILDAS, SCHED, HEASoft (Swift/XRT tools), IRAF, SExtractor.

Programming

 Python, R language, IDL language for Visualization, Fortran, PHP, HTML, CSS, C-shell, AWK.

Databases

MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite.

Graphics & Documents

MIFX, Microsoft Office, Matplotlib, Mathematica, Matlab.

Experience

- Radio observations and data analysis. Continuum data of MeerKAT, NenuFAR, Very Large Array (VLA), Australia Telescope Compact Array (ATCA), Korean VLBI Network (KVN), VERA (VLBI Exploration of Radio Astrometry), IRAM 30m, Effelsberg Radio tele-
- **Optical observations and data analysis.** Photometry and spectroscopy with Southern Astrophysical Research Telescope (SOAR 4.1m), 1.2m telescope Kryonerion Astronomical Station of the National Observatory of Athens, ESO 1m Schmidt telescope, 24-inch telescope MSU Campus Observatory, and several smaller scopes.
- **Infrared instrumentation.** LINC-NIRVANA Near infrared imaging instrument for the Large Binocular Telescope (see PhD thesis for details).
- **Teaching/Mentoring.** I have taught classes of undergrad level such as: *Elements creation* and nucleosynthesis, Computational astronomy, Observational astronomy. Advisor of undergraduate thesis projects and co-advisor of several master and PhD students.

Publications

Updated publication list at: % NASA ADS



